Hunter McNichols (He, Him)

EDUCATOR & ENGINEER

<u>HUNTERCODES.COM</u> — <u>GITHUB.COM/WMCNICHO</u> — <u>HUNTER@HUNTERCODES.COM</u>

PROFILE

Passionate educator with two years of collegiate teaching experience and six years of software development experience seeking a doctoral degree in computer science with the long-term goal of attaining a tenure-track teaching position. Areas of research interest include natural language processing, artificial intelligence, and human-robot interaction.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA — M.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA — B.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE

2015-2016, GPA 3.64 2012-2016, GPA 3.73

HONORS: MAGNA CUM LAUDE, TRUSTEE SCHOLARSHIP

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

CITY COLLEGE OF NEW YORK: MANHATTAN, NY

2020-PRESENT

ADJUNCT LECTURER

- Designed course in Al fundamentals, including current industry trends
- Topics include: rational-agent paradigm, search algorithms, representations in machine learning, foundations of computer vision, and natural language processing
- Coursework includes: practical coding exercises using SVMs, Neural Networks, and other machine learning algorithms in SciKit Learn

UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA: LOS ANGELES, CA

2014

TEACHING ASSISTANT

- Instructed undergraduates on fundamental C++ programming concepts during lab
- · Reviewed and critiqued code from new programmers, emphasizing best practices

WORK EXPERIENCE

HUNTERCODES: BROOKLYN, NY

2019-PRESENT

BUSINESS OWNER & SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Partnered with small businesses and startups to build out new software business ventures
- · Planned, organized, and developed a variety of projects from web applications to data pipelines
- View my portfolio: huntercodes.com/portfolio

APPLE INC: CUPERTINO, CA

2016-2019

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - SIRI

- · Refined dialog frameworks used by teams of designers and engineers
- · Created and taught 'Introduction to Siri Development' workshop at Siri University
- Pioneered internal debugger tools for VSCode to streamline developer workflows
- · Refined platforms across the stack written in Java, TypeScript, Python, and Objective-C

APPLE INC: CUPERTINO, CA 2015

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

- Created a Siri prototyping app for designers to experiment with new Siri interactions
- · Developed a full-stack web application for designers to prototype Siri interactions
- Built an iPhone app in Swift which downloads the interactions and replays them

BLUEBEAM INC: PASADENA,CA

2014

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

- Prototyped a geofence-based iPad application for use on construction sites
- · Built iPad application in Swift integrating with Gimbal "iBeacon" technology
- · Worked collaboratively in Git with a small team of engineers
- Measured effectiveness of application in construction environments

OTHER PROJECTS

DEEP LEARNING PROJECT. SLIPPI-AI: REMOTE

2021-PRESENT

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTOR

- · Integrated new neural architectures into deep learning project
- Assembled Transformer-inspired network using TensorFlow and Sonnet
- · Analyzed training outcomes for various learning rate cycles and model hyper-parameters
- View source code: https://github.com/vladfi1/slippi-ai

INTERACTION LAB, UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA: LOS ANGELES, CA SENIOR CAPSTONE PROJECT

2016

- · Worked with PhD students under PI Maja Matarić to create a social robotics experience
- · Built web application game played with stationary robot via tablet
- Integrated application with robot controls via Robot Operating System (ROS) libraries
- Experimented with using bezier curves for smoother robotic movements
- View Demo: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jDC4gEA5FE0

SKILLS

Frameworks: TensorFlow (Keras/Sonnet), SciKit Learn, React.js, AWS Lambda, ROS

<u>Languages</u>: Python, JavaScript, Java, Objective-C, C++, TypeScript

Pedagogical: Course Development, Virtual Instruction, Classroom Management